import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData : ExamData={
    title: "Overview",
  questions: [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "An aircraft’s mass is a result of:",
    "options": [
      "its weight.",
      "how big it is.",
      "how much matter it contains.",
      "its volume."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "The unit of mass is the:",
    "options": [
      "joule.",
      "watt.",
      "newton.",
      "kilogram."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "The definition of a force is:",
    "options": [
      "that which causes a reaction to take place.",
      "thrust and drag only.",
      "a push or a pull.",
      "the result of an applied input."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "The unit of force is the:",
    "options": [
      "mass-kilogram.",
      "newton-metre.",
      "joule.",
      "newton."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The unit of weight is the:",
    "options": [
      "kilogram.",
      "newton.",
      "watt.",
      "kilowatt."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Weight is the result of:",
    "options": [
      "the force on mass due to gravity.",
      "the action of a falling mass.",
      "how much matter the object contains.",
      "the rate of mass per unit area."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "About which point does an aircraft rotate?",
    "options": [
      "The wings.",
      "The main undercarriage.",
      "The centre of gravity.",
      "The rudder."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "If a force is applied to a mass and the mass does not move:",
    "options": [
      "work is done even though there is no movement of the mass.",
      "work is done only if the mass moves a long way.",
      "power is exerted, but no work is done.",
      "no work is done."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "The unit of work is called the:",
    "options": [
      "pascal.",
      "joule.",
      "watt.",
      "kilogram."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The unit of power is called the:",
    "options": [
      "joule.",
      "newton-metre.",
      "watt.",
      "metre per second."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "If a force of 20 newtons moves a mass 5 metres:\n1 - the work done is 100 Nm\n2 - the work done is 100 joules\n3 - the work done is 4 joules\n4 - the work done is 0.25 joules\n\nThe correct statements are:",
    "options": [
      "1 only.",
      "1 and 3.",
      "1 and 2.",
      "2 only."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "If a force of 50 newtons is applied to a 10 kg mass and the mass moves 10 metres and a force of 50 newtons is applied to a 100 kg mass which moves 10 metres:",
    "options": [
      "the work done is the same in both cases.",
      "less work is done to the 10 kg mass.",
      "more work is done to the 10 kg mass.",
      "more work is done to the 100 kg mass."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "The definition of power is:",
    "options": [
      "the rate of force applied.",
      "the rate of movement per second.",
      "the rate of doing work.",
      "the rate of applied force."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "If a force of 500 newtons moves a mass 1000 metres in 2 mins, the power used is:",
    "options": [
      "4167 watts.",
      "250 kilowatts.",
      "1 megawatt.",
      "4 watts."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Kinetic energy is:",
    "options": [
      "the energy a mass possesses due to its position in space.",
      "the energy a mass possesses when a force has been applied.",
      "the energy a mass possesses due to the force of gravity.",
      "the energy a mass possesses because of its motion."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "The unit of kinetic energy is the:",
    "options": [
      "joule.",
      "metre per second.",
      "watt.",
      "newton-metre per second."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "When considering kinetic energy:\n1 - a moving mass can apply a force by being brought to rest.\n2 - kinetic energy is the energy possessed by a body because of its motion.\n3 - if a body’s kinetic energy is increased, a force must have been applied.\n4 - kinetic energy = ½  m V²  joules.\n\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "options": [
      "1 and 2.",
      "1, 2, 3 and 4.",
      "4 only.",
      "2 and 4."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "The property of inertia is said to be:",
    "options": [
      "the energy possessed by a body because of its motion.",
      "the opposition which a body offers to a change in motion.",
      "that every action has an equal and opposite reaction.",
      "the quantity of motion possessed by a body."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "Considering Newton’s first law of motion:\n1 - a body is said to have energy if it has the ability to do work.\n2 - the amount of energy a body possesses is measured by the amount of work it can do.\n3 - a body will tend to remain at rest, or in uniform motion in a straight line, unless acted upon by an external force.\n4 - to move a stationary object or to make a moving object change its direction, a force must be applied.\n\nThe combination with the correct statements is:",
    "options": [
      "3 and 4.",
      "3 only.",
      "1 and 2.",
      "1, 2, 3 and 4."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Considering Newton’s second law of motion:\n1 - every action has an equal and opposite reaction.\n2 - if the same force is applied, the larger the mass the slower the acceleration.\n3 - if two forces are applied to the same mass, the bigger the force the greater the acceleration.\n4 - the acceleration of a body from a state of rest, or uniform motion in a straight line, is proportional to the applied force and inversely proportional to the mass.\n\nThe combination of true statements is:",
    "options": [
      "1 only.",
      "1, 2, 3 and 4.",
      "2, 3, and 4.",
      "3 and 4."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Newton’s third law of motion states:",
    "options": [
      "the energy possessed by a mass is inversely proportional to its velocity.",
      "every force has an equal and opposite inertia.",
      "for every force there is an action.",
      "every action has an equal and opposite reaction."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "The definition of velocity is the:",
    "options": [
      "rate of change of acceleration.",
      "rate of change of displacement.",
      "the quantity of motion possessed by a body.",
      "the acceleration of a body in direct proportion to its mass."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "When considering acceleration:\n1 - acceleration is the rate of change of velocity.\n2 - the units of acceleration are metres per second.\n3 - the units of acceleration are kilogram-metres per second.\n4 - the units of acceleration are seconds per metre per metre.\n\nThe combination of correct statements is:",
    "options": [
      "4 only.",
      "1 and 4.",
      "1 only.",
      "1 and 2."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "The definition of momentum is:",
    "options": [
      "the quantity of mass possessed by a body.",
      "the quantity of inertia possessed by a body.",
      "the quantity of motion possessed by a body.",
      "the opposition which a body offers to a change in velocity."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "A force of 24 newtons moves a 10 kg mass 60 metres in 1 minute. The power used is:\n1 - 24 watts.\n2 - 240 watts.\n3 - force times distance moved in one second.\n4 - force times the distance the mass is moved in one second.\n\nWhich of the preceding statements are correct:",
    "options": [
      "1 and 3.",
      "1, 3 and 4.",
      "2 and 4.",
      "4 only."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "When considering momentum:\n1 - momentum is the quantity of motion possessed by a body.\n2 - momentum is the tendency of a body to continue in motion after being placed in motion.\n3 - a mass of 2000 kg moving at 55 m/s has 110 000 kg-m/s of momentum.\n4 - a large mass moving at 50 m/s will have less momentum than a small mass moving at 50 m/s.\n\nThe correct combination of statements is:",
    "options": [
      "1 and 3.",
      "1, 2, 3 and 4.",
      "1, 2 and 3.",
      "2, 3 and 4."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  }
]
}
